# ANIL KUL

I am a fast-learning computer engineer that focus on NLP and generative AI. I worked on lots of different domains within AI domain such as computer vision, time series analysis, etc. I created product pipelines that uses LLMs and other ML models. Additionally, I have a strong software engineering experience. I am a team player and have good communication skills.



#### CONTACT

anil.kults@gmail.com

**49** 177 3058163

Munich, Germany

@anilkul98

@ Portfolio website

in Anıl Kul

# **SKILLS**

#### **Data Engineering**

**PySpark Databricks Pandas Pydantic PostgreSQL** 

#### Generative Al

**OpenAl APIs** Langchain open-source LLMs

#### ML Knowledge & Tools

torch, TF, sklearn **Computer Vision** 

## Software Engineering

Backend(FastAPI) frontend(React) **Unit Testing Databases Programming Languages** 

**Python JavaScript** Java

#### CI/CD & Deployment Tools

Git **Docker Jenkins** 

#### Soft Skills

I have presentation, team management, strategic planning and business development experiences due to my startup experience.

#### Languages

English German

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- ▼ Best Newcomer Team award in Hackmakers Formula AI Hack 2022
- ▼ Vehbi Koc Scholar (3.5+ SPA)
- ▼ VP of IEEE student branch

## EDUCATION

**10/2021 - 08/2023** 

**♀** Technical University of Munich

GPA: 2.0 (German system 1.0 is top score.)

09/2016 - 06/2021

**♥ Koc University**, Istanbul

GPA: 3.31 / 4.0

**1** 09/2017 - 06/2021

**♥ Koc University**, Istanbul GPA: 3.31 / 4.0

**Bachelor of Computer Engineering** 

**Master of Computer Science** 

**Bachelor of Business Administration** 

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## 08/2022 - Present

**SAP** - Software Engineer Generative AI **Q** Germany, Munich

Job Description: Data source specific chatbots using LLMs. Technologies: Langchain, OpenAl APIs, Vector DBs.

**1** 03/2022 - 08/2023

**SAP** - Working Student • Germany Munich

Thesis: Fact-aware LLMs based on Knowledge Graphs (KGs). KG chatbot is implemented.

**11/2021 - 03/2022** 

**Avantgarde** - ML Engineer Germany, Munich

Job Definition: Facial expression extraction pipeline with video input. (age, emotion..)

**1** 03/2021 - 11/2021

**Dcipher Analytics** - ML Engineer **♀** istanbul **Projects:** 

- Biodiversity Detection From Satellite Images: The aim of the project is detecting the areas with high biodiversity from satellite images that are taken from Sentinel2 API

- Acute Otitis Media Diagnose: The otoscope videos are used for training and product level. Worked with Autoencoders and clustering for frame selection from videos.

- Tooth Decay Diagnose: The bitewing Xrays has used for training and product level. Decayed tooth and the the areas are determined with the help of DL classifiers and class activation maps.

**6** 06/2020 - 03/2021

**Koc University IUI Lab** - Research Asst.

Project: The aim of the project is extraction of Stylized Powerpoint slides from offline and online handwritten documents. or this project, I am working with tensorflow and OpenCv . We are using the YOLO, CNN and EAST models in our pipeline.

#### **PROJECTS**

## Text Guided 3D Shape Manipulation:

GitHub Repository

It is a GAN application. Pretrained DeepSDF model is used as a generative model. With the help of Clip model the textual feedback is gathered and with latent code manipulation target 3D shape is generated.

Multiple Object Tracking:

GitHub Repository

Pretrained FastRCNN used for human detection and GNNs trained for the tracking. MOT16 dataset is used for implementation.

Object Detection For Pos Machines

GitHub Repository

This mobile application is developed for Android POS machines to authomize the entering foods to the system and getting the price. Alex AB's YOLO v4 implementation is used.

**Smart Cooking Assistant** 

GitHub Repository

A mobile app that can identify food type from Image, give nutrition and recipe information. Also it is integrated with virtual market applications for easier grocery ordering. A new Turkish food dataset is created from internet sources and Inception-v3 model is used as a classifier